
			<id-00012>
				<abilities>
					<oathofdevotion>
						<level type="number">1</level>
						<name type="string">Oath of Devotion</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>The Oath of Devotion binds a paladin to the loftiest ideals of justice, virtue, and order. Sometimes called cavaliers, white knights, or holy warriors, these paladins meet the ideal of the knight in shining armor, acting with honor in pursuit of justice and the greater good. They hold themselves to the highest standards of conduct, and some, for better or worse, hold the rest of the world to the same standards. Many who swear this oath are devoted to gods of law and good and use their gods' tenets as the measure of their devotion. They hold angels-the perfect servants of good-as their ideals, and incorporate images of angelic wings into their helmets or coats of arms.</p>
							<h>Features</h>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.tenetsofdevotion3">Tenets of Devotion</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.oathspells_devotion_3">Oath Spells (Devotion)</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.channeldivinity_devotion_3">Channel Divinity (Devotion)</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.auraofdevotion7">Aura of Devotion</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.purityofspirit15">Purity of Spirit</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.holynimbus20">Holy Nimbus</link>
							</linklist>
						</text>
					</oathofdevotion>
					<oathoftheancients>
						<level type="number">1</level>
						<name type="string">Oath of the Ancients</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>The Oath of the Ancients is as old as the race of elves and the rituals of the druids. Sometimes called fey knights, green knights, or horned knights, paladins who swear this oath cast their lot with the side of the light in the cosmic struggle against darkness because they love the beautiful and life-giving things of the world, not necessarily because they believe in principles of honor, courage, and justice. They adorn their armor and clothing with images of growing things-leaves, antlers, or flowers-to reflect their commitment to preserving life and light in the world.</p>
							<h>Features</h>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.tenetsoftheancients3">Tenets of the Ancients</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.oathspells_ancients_3">Oath Spells (Ancients)</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.channeldivinity_ancients_3">Channel Divinity (Ancients)</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.auraofwarding7">Aura of Warding</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.undyingsentinel15">Undying Sentinel</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.elderchampion20">Elder Champion</link>
							</linklist>
						</text>
					</oathoftheancients>
					<oathofvengeance>
						<level type="number">1</level>
						<name type="string">Oath of Vengeance</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>The Oath of Vengeance is a solemn commitment to punish those who have committed a grievous sin. When evil forces slaughter helpless villagers, when an entire people turns against the will of the gods, when a thieves' guild grows too violent and powerful, when a dragon rampages through the countryside-at times like these, paladins arise and swear an Oath of Vengeance to set right that which has gone wrong. To these paladins-sometimes called avengers or dark knights-their own purity is not as important as delivering justice.</p>
							<h>Features</h>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.tenetsofvengeance3">Tenets of Vengeance</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.oathspells_vengeance_3">Oath Spells (Vengeance)</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.channeldivinity_vengeance_3">Channel Divinity (Vengeance)</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.relentlessavenger7">Relentless Avenger</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.soulofvengeance15">Soul of Vengeance</link>
								<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="....features.avengingangel20">Avenging Angel</link>
							</linklist>
						</text>
					</oathofvengeance>
				</abilities>
				<equipment>
					<standard>
						<group type="string">standard</group>
					</standard>
				</equipment>
				<features>
					<abilityscoreimprovement12>
						<level type="number">12</level>
						<name type="string">Ability Score Improvement</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
						</text>
					</abilityscoreimprovement12>
					<abilityscoreimprovement16>
						<level type="number">16</level>
						<name type="string">Ability Score Improvement</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
						</text>
					</abilityscoreimprovement16>
					<abilityscoreimprovement19>
						<level type="number">19</level>
						<name type="string">Ability Score Improvement</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
						</text>
					</abilityscoreimprovement19>
					<abilityscoreimprovement4>
						<level type="number">4</level>
						<name type="string">Ability Score Improvement</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
						</text>
					</abilityscoreimprovement4>
					<abilityscoreimprovement8>
						<level type="number">8</level>
						<name type="string">Ability Score Improvement</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
						</text>
					</abilityscoreimprovement8>
					<auraofcourage10>
						<level type="number">10</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Courage</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be frightened while you are conscious.</p>
							<p>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofcourage10>
					<auraofcourage18>
						<level type="number">18</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Courage</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be frightened while you are conscious.</p>
							<p>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofcourage18>
					<auraofdevotion18>
						<level type="number">18</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Devotion</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 7th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be charmed while you are conscious. At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofdevotion18>
					<auraofdevotion7>
						<level type="number">7</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Devotion</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 7th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be charmed while you are conscious. At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofdevotion7>
					<auraofprotection18>
						<level type="number">18</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Protection</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</p>
							<p>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofprotection18>
					<auraofprotection6>
						<level type="number">6</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Protection</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</p>
							<p>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofprotection6>
					<auraofwarding18>
						<level type="number">18</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Warding</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Beginning at 7th level, ancient magic lies so heavily upon you that it forms an eldritch ward. You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you have resistance to damage from spells.</p>
							<p>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofwarding18>
					<auraofwarding7>
						<level type="number">7</level>
						<name type="string">Aura of Warding</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Beginning at 7th level, ancient magic lies so heavily upon you that it forms an eldritch ward. You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you have resistance to damage from spells.</p>
							<p>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
						</text>
					</auraofwarding7>
					<avengingangel20>
						<level type="number">20</level>
						<name type="string">Avenging Angel</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Vengeance</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>At 20th level, you can assume the form of an angelic avenger. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 hour, you gain the following benefits:</p>
							<list>
								<li>Wings sprout from your back and grant you a flying speed of 60 feet.</li>
								<li>You emanate an aura of menace in a 30-foot radius. The first time any enemy creature enters the aura or starts its turn there during a battle, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage.</li>
							</list>
							<p>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
						</text>
					</avengingangel20>
					<channeldivinity_ancients_3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Channel Divinity (Ancients)</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
							<p><b>Nature's Wrath. </b>You can use your Channel Divinity to invoke primeval forces to ensnare a foe. As an action, you can cause spectral vines to spring up and reach for a creature within 10 feet of you that you can see.</p>
							<p>The creature must succeed on a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (its choice) or be restrained. While restrained by the vines, the creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, it frees itself and the vines vanish.</p>
							<p><b>Turn the Faithless. </b>You can use your Channel Divinity to utter ancient words that are painful for fey and fiends to hear. As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each fey or fiend within 30 feet of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</p>
							<p>A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</p>
							<p>If the creature's true form is concealed by an illusion, shapeshifting, or other effect, that form is revealed while it is turned.</p>
						</text>
					</channeldivinity_ancients_3>
					<channeldivinity_devotion_3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Channel Divinity (Devotion)</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
							<p><b>Sacred Weapon. </b>As an action, you can imbue one weapon that you are holding with positive energy, using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, you add your Charisma modifier to attack rolls made with that weapon (with a minimum bonus of +1). The weapon also emits bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light 20 feet beyond that. If the weapon is not already magical, it becomes magical for the duration.</p>
							<p>You can end this effect on your turn as part of any other action. If you are no longer holding or carrying this weapon, or if you fall unconscious, this effect ends.</p>
							<p><b>Turn the Unholy. </b>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring fiends and undead, using your Channel Divinity. Each fiend or undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</p>
							<p>A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</p>
						</text>
					</channeldivinity_devotion_3>
					<channeldivinity_vengeance_3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Channel Divinity (Vengeance)</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Vengeance</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
							<p><b>Abjure Enemy. </b>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer of denunciation, using your Channel Divinity. Choose one creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw, unless it is immune to being frightened. Fiends and undead have disadvantage on this saving throw.</p>
							<p>On a failed save, the creature is frightened for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. While frightened, the creature's speed is 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.</p>
							<p>On a successful save, the creature's speed is halved for 1 minute or until the creature takes any damage.</p>
							<p><b>Vow of Enmity. </b>As a bonus action, you can utter a vow of enmity against a creature you can see within 10 feet of you, using your Channel Divinity. You gain advantage on attack rolls against the creature for 1 minute or until it drops to 0 hit points or falls unconscious.</p>
						</text>
					</channeldivinity_vengeance_3>
					<cleansingtouch14>
						<level type="number">14</level>
						<name type="string">Cleansing Touch</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action to end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</p>
							<p>You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
						</text>
					</cleansingtouch14>
					<divinehealth3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Divine Health</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</p>
						</text>
					</divinehealth3>
					<divinesense1>
						<level type="number">1</level>
						<name type="string">Divine Sense</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance).</p>
							<p>Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the hallow spell.</p>
							<p>You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
						</text>
					</divinesense1>
					<divinesmite2>
						<level type="number">2</level>
						<name type="string">Divine Smite</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend to a maximum of 6d8.</p>
						</text>
					</divinesmite2>
					<elderchampion20>
						<level type="number">20</level>
						<name type="string">Elder Champion</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>At 20th level, you can assume the form of an ancient force of nature, taking on an appearance you choose. For example, your skin might turn green or take on a bark-like texture, your hair might become leafy or mosslike, or you might sprout antlers or a lion-like mane. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
							<list>
								<li>At the start of each of your turns, you regain 10 hit points.</li>
								<li>Whenever you cast a paladin spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can cast it using a bonus action instead.</li>
								<li>Enemy creatures within 10 feet of you have disadvantage on saving throws against your paladin spells and Channel Divinity options.</li>
							</list>
							<p>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
						</text>
					</elderchampion20>
					<extraattack5>
						<level type="number">5</level>
						<name type="string">Extra Attack</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
						</text>
					</extraattack5>
					<fightingstyle2>
						<level type="number">2</level>
						<name type="string">Fighting Style</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
							<p><b>Defense</b></p>
							<p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
							<p><b>Dueling</b></p>
							<p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
							<p><b>Great Weapon Fighting</b></p>
							<p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
							<p><b>Protection</b></p>
							<p>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</p>
						</text>
					</fightingstyle2>
					<holynimbus20>
						<level type="number">20</level>
						<name type="string">Holy Nimbus</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>At 20th level, as an action, you can emanate an aura of sunlight. For 1 minute, bright light shines from you in a 30-foot radius, and dim light shines 30 feet beyond that. Whenever an enemy creature starts its turn in the bright light, the creature takes 10 radiant damage.</p>
							<p>In addition, for the duration, you have advantage on saving throws against spells cast by fiends or undead. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
						</text>
					</holynimbus20>
					<improveddivinesmite11>
						<level type="number">11</level>
						<name type="string">Improved Divine Smite</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry divine power with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.</p>
						</text>
					</improveddivinesmite11>
					<layonhands1>
						<level type="number">1</level>
						<name type="string">Lay on Hands</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x5. As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</p>
							<p>Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately for each one.</p>
							<p>This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</p>
						</text>
					</layonhands1>
					<oathspells_ancients_3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Oath Spells (Ancients)</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</p>
							<h>Oath of the Ancients Spells</h>
							<p><b>Paladin Level - Spell</b></p>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.ensnaringstrike@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>3rd - Ensnaring Strike</linklist>
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.speakwithanimals@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>3rd - Speak with Animals
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.moonbeam@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>5th - Moonbeam
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.mistystep@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>5th - Misty Step
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.plantgrowth@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>9th - Plant Growth
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.protectionfromenergy@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>9th - Protection from Energy
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.icestorm@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>13th - Ice Storm
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.stoneskin@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>13th - Stoneskin
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.communewithnature@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>17th - Commune With Nature
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.treestride@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>17th - Tree Stride
						</text>
					</oathspells_ancients_3>
					<oathspells_devotion_3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Oath Spells (Devotion)</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</p>
							<h>Oath of Devotion Spells</h>
							<p><b>Paladin Level - Spell</b></p>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.protectionfromevilandgood@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>3rd - Protection from Evil and Good</linklist>
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.sanctuary@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>3rd - Sanctuary
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.lesserrestoration@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>5th - Lesser Restoration
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.zoneoftruth@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>5th - Zone of Truth
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.beaconofhope@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>9th - Beacon of Hope
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.dispelmagic@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>9th - Dispel Magic
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.freedomofmovement@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>13th - Freedom of Movement
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.guardianoffaith@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>13th - Guardian of Faith
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.commune@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>17th - Commune
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.flamestrike@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>17th - Flame Strike
						</text>
					</oathspells_devotion_3>
					<oathspells_vengeance_3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Oath Spells (Vengeance)</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Vengeance</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</p>
							<h>Oath of Vengeance Spells</h>
							<p><b>Paladin Level - Spell</b></p>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.bane@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>3rd - Bane</linklist>
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.hunter_smark@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>3rd - Hunter's Mark
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.holdperson@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>5th - Hold Person
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.mistystep@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>5th - Misty Step
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.haste@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>9th - Haste
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.protectionfromenergy@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>9th - Protection from Energy
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.banishment@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>13th - Banishment
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.dimensiondoor@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>13th - Dimension Door
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.holdmonster@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>17th - Hold Monster
								<link class="reference_spell" recordname="reference.spelldata.scrying@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Spell: </b></link>17th - Scrying
						</text>
					</oathspells_vengeance_3>
					<purityofspirit15>
						<level type="number">15</level>
						<name type="string">Purity of Spirit</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Beginning at 15th level, you are always under the effects of a protection from evil and good spell.</p>
						</text>
					</purityofspirit15>
					<relentlessavenger7>
						<level type="number">7</level>
						<name type="string">Relentless Avenger</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Vengeance</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>By 7th level, your supernatural focus helps you close off a foe's retreat. When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, you can move up to half your speed immediately after the attack and as part of the same reaction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
						</text>
					</relentlessavenger7>
					<sacredoath3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Sacred Oath</name>
						<specializationchoice type="number">1</specializationchoice>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When you reach 3rd level, you swear the oath that binds you as a paladin forever. Up to this time you have been in a preparatory stage, committed to the path but not yet sworn to it. Now you choose the Oath of Devotion, the Oath of the Ancients, or the Oath of Vengeance, all detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
							<p>Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 15th, and 20th level. Those features include oath spells and the Channel Divinity feature.</p>
							<p><b>Oath Spells</b></p>
							<p>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
							<p>If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</p>
							<p><b>Breaking Your Oath</b></p>
							<p>A paladin tries to hold to the highest standards of conduct, but even the most virtuous paladin is fallible. Sometimes the right path proves too demanding, sometimes a situation calls for the lesser of two evils, and sometimes the heat of emotion causes a paladin to transgress his or her oath.</p>
							<p>A paladin who has broken a vow typically seeks absolution from a cleric who shares his or her faith or from another paladin of the same order. The paladin might spend an all night vigil in prayer as a sign of penitence, or undertake a fast or similar act of self-denial. After a rite of confession and forgiveness, the paladin starts fresh.</p>
							<p>If a paladin willfully violates his or her oath and shows no sign of repentance, the consequences can be more serious. At the DM's discretion, an impenitent paladin might be forced to abandon this class and adopt another, or perhaps to take the Oathbreaker paladin option that appears in the Dungeon Master's Guide.</p>
							<p><b>Channel Divinity</b></p>
							<p>Your oath allows you to channel divine energy to fuel magical effects. Each Channel Divinity option provided by your oath explains how to use it.</p>
							<p>When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which option to use. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</p>
							<p>Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your paladin spell save DC.</p>
						</text>
					</sacredoath3>
					<soulofvengeance15>
						<level type="number">15</level>
						<name type="string">Soul of Vengeance</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Vengeance</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 15th level, the authority with which you speak your Vow of Enmity gives you greater power over your foe. When a creature under the effect of your Vow of Enmity makes an attack, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature if it is within range.</p>
						</text>
					</soulofvengeance15>
					<spellcasting2>
						<level type="number">2</level>
						<name type="string">Spellcasting</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list.</p>
							<linklist>
								<link class="reference_colindex" recordname="reference.spelllists.paladin@DD PHB Deluxe">Paladin Spells</link>
							</linklist>
							<p><b>Preparing and Casting Spells</b></p>
							<p>The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your paladin spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
							<p>You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells. You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
							<p><b>Spellcasting Ability</b></p>
							<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
							<p><b>Spell save DC </b>= 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
							<p><b>Spell attack modifier </b>= your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
							<p><b>Spellcasting Focus</b></p>
							<p>You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.</p>
						</text>
					</spellcasting2>
					<tenetsofdevotion3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Tenets of Devotion</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Devotion</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Though the exact words and strictures of the Oath of Devotion vary, paladins of this oath share these tenets.</p>
							<p><b>Honesty. </b>Don't lie or cheat. Let your word be your promise.</p>
							<p><b>Courage. </b>Never fear to act, though caution is wise.</p>
							<p><b>Compassion. </b>Aid others, protect the weak, and punish those who threaten them. Show mercy to your foes, but temper it with wisdom.</p>
							<p><b>Honor. </b>Treat others with fairness, and let your honorable deeds be an example to them. Do as much good as possible while causing the least amount of harm.</p>
							<p><b>Duty. </b>Be responsible for your actions and their consequences, protect those entrusted to your care, and obey those who have just authority over you.</p>
						</text>
					</tenetsofdevotion3>
					<tenetsoftheancients3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Tenets of the Ancients</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>The tenets of the Oath of the Ancients have been preserved for uncounted centuries. This oath emphasizes the principles of good above any concerns of law or chaos. Its four central principles are simple.</p>
							<p><b>Kindle the Light. </b>Through your acts of mercy, kindness, and forgiveness, kindle the light of hope in the world, beating back despair.</p>
							<p><b>Shelter the Light. </b>Where there is good, beauty, love, and laughter in the world, stand against the wickedness that would swallow it. Where life flourishes, stand against the forces that would render it barren.</p>
							<p><b>Preserve Your Own Light. </b>Delight in song and laughter, in beauty and art. If you allow the light to die in your own heart, you can't preserve it in the world.</p>
							<p><b>Be the Light. </b>Be a glorious beacon for all who live in despair. Let the light of your joy and courage shine forth in all your deeds.</p>
						</text>
					</tenetsoftheancients3>
					<tenetsofvengeance3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Tenets of Vengeance</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of Vengeance</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>The tenets of the Oath of Vengeance vary by paladin, but all the tenets revolve around punishing wrongdoers by any means necessary. Paladins who uphold these tenets are willing to sacrifice even their own righteousness to mete out justice upon those who do evil, so the paladins are often neutral or lawful neutral in alignment. The core principles of the tenets are brutally simple.</p>
							<p><b>Fight the Greater Evil. </b>Faced with a choice of fighting my sworn foes or combating a lesser evil. I choose the greater evil.</p>
							<p><b>No Mercy for the Wicked. </b>Ordinary foes might win my mercy, but my sworn enemies do not.</p>
							<p><b>By Any Means Necessary. </b>My qualms can't get in the way of exterminating my foes.</p>
							<p><b>Restitution. </b>If my foes wreak ruin on the world, it is because I failed to stop them. I must help those harmed by their misdeeds.</p>
						</text>
					</tenetsofvengeance3>
					<undyingsentinel15>
						<level type="number">15</level>
						<name type="string">Undying Sentinel</name>
						<specialization type="string">Oath of the Ancients</specialization>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Starting at 15th level, when you are reduced to 0 hit points and are not killed outright, you can choose to drop to 1 hit point instead. Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest. Additionally, you suffer none of the drawbacks of old age, and you can't be aged magically.</p>
						</text>
					</undyingsentinel15>
				</features>
				<hp>
					<hitdice>
						<name type="string">Hit Dice</name>
						<text type="string">1d10 per paladin level</text>
					</hitdice>
					<hitpointsat1stlevel>
						<name type="string">Hit Points at 1st Level</name>
						<text type="string">10 + your Constitution modifier</text>
					</hitpointsat1stlevel>
					<hitpointsathigherlevels>
						<name type="string">Hit Points at Higher Levels</name>
						<text type="string">1d 10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per paladin level after 1st</text>
					</hitpointsathigherlevels>
				</hp>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<multiclassfeatures>
					<channeldivinity3>
						<level type="number">3</level>
						<name type="string">Channel Divinity</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>If you already have the Channel Divinity feature and gain a level in a class that also grants the feature, you gain the Channel Divinity effects granted by that class, but getting the feature again doesn't give you an additional use of it. You gain additional uses only when you reach a class level that explicitly grants them to you. For example, if you are a cleric 6/paladin 4, you can use Channel Divinity twice between rests because you are high enough level in the cleric class to have more uses. Whenever you use the feature, you can choose any of the Channel Divinity effects available to you from your two classes.</p>
						</text>
					</channeldivinity3>
					<extraattack5>
						<level type="number">5</level>
						<name type="string">Extra Attack</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>If you gain the Extra Attack class feature from more than one class, the features don't add together. You can't make more than two attacks with this feature unless it says you do (as the fighter's version of Extra Attack does). Similarly, the warlock's eldritch invocation Thirsting Blade doesn't give you additional attacks if you also have Extra Attack.</p>
						</text>
					</extraattack5>
					<spellcasting2>
						<level type="number">2</level>
						<name type="string">Spellcasting</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Your capacity for spellcasting depends partly on your combined levels in all your spellcasting classes and partly on your individual levels in those classes. Once you have the Spellcasting feature from more than one class, use the rules below. If you multiclass but have the Spellcasting feature from only one class, you follow the rules as described in that class.</p>
							<p><b>Spells Known and Prepared. </b>You determine what spells you know and can prepare for each class individually, as if you were a single-classed member of that class. If you are a ranger 4/wizard 3, for example, you know three 1st-level ranger spells based on your levels in the ranger class. As 3rd-level wizard, you know three wizard cantrips, and your spellbook contains ten wizard spells, two of which (the two you gained when you reached 3rd level as a wizard) can be 2nd-level spells. If your Intelligence is 16, you can prepare six wizard spells from your spellbook.</p>
							<p>Each spell you know and prepare is associated with one of your classes, and you use the spellcasting ability of that class when you cast the spell. Similarly, a spellcasting focus, such as a holy symbol, can be used only for the spells from the class associated with that focus.</p>
							<p><b>Spell Slots. </b>You determine your available spell slots by adding together all your levels in the bard, cleric, druid, sorcerer, and wizard classes, half your levels (rounded down) in the paladin and ranger classes, and a third of your fighter or rogue levels (rounded down) if you have the Eldritch Knight or the Arcane Trickster feature. Use this total to determine your spell slots by consulting the Multiclass Spellcaster table.</p>
							<p>If you have more than one spellcasting class, this table might give you spell slots of a level that is higher than the spells you know or can prepare. You can use those slots, but only to cast your lower-level spells. If a lower level spell that you cast, like burning hands, has an enhanced effect when cast using a higher-level slot, you can use the enhanced effect, even though you don't have any spells of that higher level.</p>
							<p>For example, if you are the aforementioned ranger 4/ wizard 3, you count as a 5th-level character when determining your spell slots: you have four 1st-level slots, three 2nd-level slots, and two 3rd-level slots. However, you don't know any 3rd-level spells, nor do you know any 2nd-level ranger spells. You can use the spell slots of those levels to cast the spells you do know-and potentially enhance their effects.</p>
							<p><b>Pact Magic. </b>If you have both the Spellcasting class feature and the Pact Magic class feature from the warlock class, you can use the spell slots you gain from the Pact Magic feature to cast spells you know or have prepared from classes with the Spellcasting class feature, and you can use the spell slots you gain from the Spellcasting class feature to cast warlock spells you know.</p>
							<p><b>MulticlassSpellcaster:</b></p>
							<p><b>SpellSlotsperSpellLevel</b></p>
							<table>
								<tr>
									<td><b>Lvl.</b></td>
									<td><b>1st</b></td>
									<td><b>2nd</b></td>
									<td><b>3rd</b></td>
									<td><b>4th</b></td>
									<td><b>5th</b></td>
									<td><b>6th</b></td>
									<td><b>7th</b></td>
									<td><b>8th</b></td>
									<td><b>9th</b></td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>1st</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>2nd</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>3rd</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>2-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>4th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>5th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>6th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>7th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>8th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>9th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>10th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>11th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>12th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>13th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>14th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>15th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>16th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>-</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>17th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>18th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>19th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
								</tr>
								<tr>
									<td>20th</td>
									<td>4</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>3</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>2</td>
									<td>1</td>
									<td>1</td>
								</tr>
							</table>
						</text>
					</spellcasting2>
				</multiclassfeatures>
				<multiclassproficiencies>
					<armor>
						<name type="string">Armor</name>
						<text type="string">Light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
					</armor>
					<weapons>
						<name type="string">Weapons</name>
						<text type="string">Simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
					</weapons>
				</multiclassproficiencies>
				<name type="string">Paladin</name>
				<proficiencies>
					<armor>
						<name type="string">Armor</name>
						<text type="string">All armor, shields</text>
					</armor>
					<savingthrows>
						<name type="string">Saving Throws</name>
						<text type="string">Wisdom, Charisma</text>
					</savingthrows>
					<skills>
						<name type="string">Skills</name>
						<text type="string">Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
					</skills>
					<tools>
						<name type="string">Tools</name>
						<text type="string">None</text>
					</tools>
					<weapons>
						<name type="string">Weapons</name>
						<text type="string">Simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
					</weapons>
				</proficiencies>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<h>Paladin</h>
					<p>Clad in plate armor that gleams in the sunlight despite the dust and grime of long travel, a human lays down her sword and shield and places her hands on a mortally wounded man. Divine radiance shines from her hands, the man's wounds knit closed, and his eyes open wide with amazement.</p>
					<p>A dwarf crouches behind an outcrop, his black cloak making him nearly invisible in the night, and watches an orc war band celebrating its recent victory. Silently, he stalks into their midst and whispers an oath, and two orcs are dead before they even realize he is there.</p>
					<p>Silver hair shining in a shaft of light that seems to illuminate only him, an elf laughs with exultation. His spear flashes like his eyes as he jabs again and again at a twisted giant, until at last his light overcomes its hideous darkness.</p>
					<p>Whatever their origin and their mission, paladins are united by their oaths to stand against the forces of evil. Whether sworn before a god's altar and the witness of a priest, in a sacred glade before nature spirits and fey beings, or in a moment of desperation and grief with the dead as the only witness, a paladin's oath is a powerful bond. It is a source of power that turns a devout warrior into a blessed champion.</p>
					<h>The Cause of Righteousness</h>
					<p>A paladin swears to uphold justice and righteousness, to stand with the good things of the world against the encroaching darkness, and to hunt the forces of evil wherever they lurk. Different paladins focus on various aspects of the cause of righteousness, but all are bound by the oaths that grant them power to do their sacred work. Although many paladins are devoted to gods of good, a paladin's power comes as much from a commitment to justice itself as it does from a god. Paladins train for years to learn the skills of combat, mastering a variety of weapons and armor. Even so, their martial skills are secondary to the magical power they wield: power to heal the sick and injured, to smite the wicked and the undead, and to protect the innocent and those who join them in the fight for justice.</p>
					<h>Beyond the Mundane Life</h>
					<p>Almost by definition, the life of a paladin is an adventuring life. Unless a lasting injury has taken him or her away from adventuring for a time, every paladin lives on the front lines of the cosmic struggle against evil. Fighters are rare enough among the ranks of the militias and armies of the world, but even fewer people can claim the true calling of a paladin. When they do receive the call, these warriors turn from their former occupations and take up arms to fight evil. Sometimes their oaths lead them into the service of the crown as leaders of elite groups of knights, but even then their loyalty is first to the cause of righteousness, not to crown and country.</p>
					<p>Adventuring paladins take their work seriously. A delve into an ancient ruin or dusty crypt can be a quest driven by a higher purpose than the acquisition of treasure. Evil lurks in dungeons and primeval forests, and even the smallest victory against it can tilt the cosmic balance away from oblivion.</p>
					<h>Creating a Paladin</h>
					<p>The most important aspect of a paladin character is the nature of his or her holy quest. Although the class features related to your oath don't appear until you reach 3rd level, plan ahead for that choice by reading the oath descriptions at the end of the class. Are you a devoted servant of good, loyal to the gods of justice and honor, a holy knight in shining armor venturing forth to smite evil? Are you a glorious champion of the light, cherishing everything beautiful that stands against the shadow, a knight whose oath descends from traditions older than many of the gods? Or are you an embittered loner sworn to take vengeance on those who have done great evil, sent as an angel of death by the gods or driven by your need for revenge? Appendix B lists many deities worshiped by paladins throughout the multiverse, such as Torm, Tyr, Heironeous, Paladine, Kiri-Jolith, Dol Arrah, the Silver Flame, Bahamut, Athena, Re-Horakhty, and Heimdall.</p>
					<p>How did you experience your call to serve as a paladin? Did you hear a whisper from an unseen god or angel while you were at prayer? Did another paladin sense the potential within you and decide to train you as a squire? Or did some terrible event-the destruction of your home, perhaps-drive you to your quests? Perhaps you stumbled into a sacred grove or a hidden elven enclave and found yourself called to protect all such refuges of goodness and beauty. Or you might have known from your earliest memories that the paladin's life was your calling, almost as if you had been sent into the world with that purpose stamped on your soul.</p>
					<p>As guardians against the forces of wickedness, paladins are rarely of any evil alignment. Most of them walk the paths of charity and justice. Consider how your alignment colors the way you pursue your holy quest and the manner in which you conduct yourself before gods and mortals. Your oath and alignment might be in harmony, or your oath might represent standards of behavior that you have not yet attained.</p>
					<h>Quick Build</h>
					<p>You can make a paladin quickly by following these suggestions. First, Strength should be your highest ability score, followed by Charisma. Second, choose the noble background.</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="reference_background" recordname="reference.backgrounddata.noble@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Background: </b></link>Noble</linklist>
						<link class="reference_background" recordname="reference.backgrounddata.nobleknight@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Background: </b></link>Noble Knight
					<p><b>The Paladin</b></p>
					<table>
						<tr>
							<td><b>Level</b></td>
							<td><b>Proficiency Bonus</b></td>
							<td colspan="3"><b>Features</b></td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>1st</td>
							<td>+2</td>
							<td colspan="3">Divine Sense, Lay on Hands</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>2nd</td>
							<td>+2</td>
							<td colspan="3">Fighting Style, Spellcasting, Divine Smite</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>3rd</td>
							<td>+2</td>
							<td colspan="3">Divine Health, Sacred Oath</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>4th</td>
							<td>+2</td>
							<td colspan="3">Ability Score Improvement</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>5th</td>
							<td>+3</td>
							<td colspan="3">Extra Attack</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>6th</td>
							<td>+3</td>
							<td colspan="3">Aura of Protection</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>7th</td>
							<td>+3</td>
							<td colspan="3">Sacred Oath feature</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>8th</td>
							<td>+3</td>
							<td colspan="3">Ability Score Improvement</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>9th</td>
							<td>+4</td>
							<td colspan="3">-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>10th</td>
							<td>+4</td>
							<td colspan="3">Aura of Courage</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>11th</td>
							<td>+4</td>
							<td colspan="3">Improved Divine Smite</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>12th</td>
							<td>+4</td>
							<td colspan="3">Ability Score Improvement</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>13th</td>
							<td>+5</td>
							<td colspan="3">-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>14th</td>
							<td>+5</td>
							<td colspan="3">Cleansing Touch</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>15th</td>
							<td>+5</td>
							<td colspan="3">Sacred Oath feature</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>16th</td>
							<td>+5</td>
							<td colspan="3">Ability Score Improvement</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>17th</td>
							<td>+6</td>
							<td colspan="3">-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>18th</td>
							<td>+6</td>
							<td colspan="3">Aura improvements</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>19th</td>
							<td>+6</td>
							<td colspan="3">Ability Score Improvement</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>20th</td>
							<td>+6</td>
							<td colspan="3">Sacred Oath feature</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
					<p><b>Spell Slots per Spell Level</b></p>
					<table>
						<tr>
							<td><b>Level</b></td>
							<td><b>1st</b></td>
							<td><b>2nd</b></td>
							<td><b>3rd</b></td>
							<td><b>4th</b></td>
							<td><b>5th</b></td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>1st</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>2nd</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>3rd</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>4th</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>5th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>6th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>7th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>8th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>9th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>10th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>11th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>12th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>-</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>13th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>1</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>14th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>1</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>15th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>16th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>2</td>
							<td>-</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>17th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>1</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>18th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>1</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>19th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>2</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>20th</td>
							<td>4</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>3</td>
							<td>2</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
					<h>Class Features</h>
					<p>As a paladin, you gain the following class features.</p>
					<h>Hit Points</h>
					<p><b>Hit Dice: </b>1d10 per paladin level</p>
					<p><b>Hit Points At 1st Level: </b>10 + your Constitution modifier</p>
					<p><b>Hit Points At Higher Levels: </b>1d 10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per paladin level after 1st</p>
					<h>Proficiencies</h>
					<p><b>Armor: </b>All armor, shields</p>
					<p><b>Weapons: </b>Simple weapons, martial weapons</p>
					<p><b>Tools: </b>None</p>
					<p><b>Saving Throws: </b>Wisdom, Charisma</p>
					<p><b>Skills: </b>Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</p>
					<h>Equipment</h>
					<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
					<list>
						<li>(a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</li>
						<li>(a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon</li>
						<li>(a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</li>
						<li>Chain mail and a holy symbol</li>
					</list>
					<linklist>
						<link class="reference_weapontable" recordname="reference.equipmentlists.weapontable@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Link: </b></link>Weapon List</linklist>
						<link class="reference_armortable" recordname="reference.equipmentlists.armortable@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Link: </b></link>Armor List
						<link class="reference_adventuringgeartable" recordname="reference.equipmentlists.adventuringgeartable@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Link: </b></link>Adventuring Gear
						<link class="reference_adventuringgeartable" recordname="reference.equipmentlists.toolstable@DD PHB Deluxe"><b>Link: </b></link>Tools
					<h>Features</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.divinesense1">Divine Sense</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.layonhands1">Lay on Hands</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.fightingstyle2">Fighting Style</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.spellcasting2">Spellcasting</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.divinesmite2">Divine Smite</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.divinehealth3">Divine Health</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.sacredoath3">Sacred Oath</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.abilityscoreimprovement4">Ability Score Improvement</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.extraattack5">Extra Attack</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.auraofprotection6">Aura of Protection</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.auraofcourage10">Aura of Courage</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.improveddivinesmite11">Improved Divine Smite</link>
						<link class="reference_classfeature" recordname="..features.cleansingtouch14">Cleansing Touch</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Sacred Oaths</h>
					<p>Becoming a paladin involves taking vows that commit the paladin to the cause of righteousness, an active path of fighting wickedness. The final oath, taken when he or she reaches 3rd level, is the culmination of all the paladin's training. Some characters with this class don't consider themselves true paladins until they have reached 3rd level and made this oath. For others, the actual swearing of the oath is a formality, an official stamp on what has always been true in the paladin's heart.</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="reference_classability" recordname="..abilities.oathofdevotion">Oath of Devotion</link>
						<link class="reference_classability" recordname="..abilities.oathoftheancients">Oath of the Ancients</link>
						<link class="reference_classability" recordname="..abilities.oathofvengeance">Oath of Vengeance</link>
					</linklist>
				</text>
			</id-00012>